Guide to the Communist Party of the United States of America Audio Collection TAM.132.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Series IV: Audio Cassette Tapes: Public Events
  - Subseries IV:A: Events
    - Rev. Bruce Southworth, W. E. B. Du Bois "To Awaken the World" (1900). Community Church, New York, NY, Feb 6, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3280)
    - Rev. Bruce Southworth, W. E. B. Du Bois "To Awaken the World" (1900). Community Church, New York, NY, Feb 6, 1983 (Box 58, Cassette 1291)
    - General Meeting at Party Headquarters. Gus Hall, Speech, Feb 9, 1983 (Box 32, Cassette 4923)
    - John Pittman, Freedom Road. Tape 1, Feb 9, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3281)
    - John Pittman, Freedom Road. Tape 2, Feb 9, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3282)
    - Gus Hall, Press Conference, Feb 11, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3283)
    - James Jackson, Freedom Road. [Tape 1?], Feb 23, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3286)
    - James Jackson, Freedom Road. [Tape 2?], Feb 23, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3287)
    - James Jackson, Freedom Road. [Tape 3?], Feb 16, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3284)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Engels, Liebknecht, Eleanor Marx and Lafargue, Biographical and Reminiscences. Unity Center, New York, NY. Tape 1, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3296)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Karl Marx by Vladimir Il'ich Lenin. Unity Center, New York, NY. Tape 2, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3301)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Gus Hall on Marx, and the Revolutionary Movement in Developed Countries. Also Includes Jarvis Tyner and Lee Dlugin. Unity Center, New York, NY (Mar 19, 1983). Tape 3, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3305)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Timor Timofeyev, Marxism and the Construction of an Advanced Socialist Society. Also Includes Erwin Marquit and Victor Perlo. Unity Center, New York, NY (Mar 19, 1983). Tape 4, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3311)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Moses Mabhida, On Marx, and the Revolutionary Movement in Developing Countries. Also Includes Leith Mullings, Lou Diskin and Gus Hall. Unity Center, New York, NY (Mar 26, 1983). Tape 5, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3316)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. James Jackson, Karl Marx and the USA. Unity Center, New York, NY (Mar 20, 1983). Tape 6, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3319)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Panel Discussing James Jackson on Karl Marx and the USA, Includes James Steele and Michael Zagarell. (Mar 20, 1983). Tape 7, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3323)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Panel Discussing James Jackson on Karl Marx and the USA, Includes James Steele and Michael Zagarell. (Mar 20, 1983). Tape 7 [2], Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3324)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Panel Discussing James Jackson on Karl Marx and the USA, Includes James Steele and Michael Zagarell. (Mar 20, 1983). Tape 7 [3], Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3326)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Hans-Joachim Radde: Marx, Conception of Socialism and Existing Socialism. Berlin, German Democratic Republic. (Mar 19, 1983). Tape 8, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3329)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Henry Winston, Marx and the Struggle for Peace in the USA. (May 22, 1983). Tape 9, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3333)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Gus Hall, 100 Years After Marx: Right on Target. Boston Community Church, MA. (Mar 20, 1983). Tape 10, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3337)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Gus Hall, Marx in Our Time - The Struggle for Peace, and Social Progress. Berlin, German Democratic Republic (Apr 11, 1983 - Apr 16, 1983). Tape 11, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3341)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Herbert Aptheker, Marx and the Social Sciences. (Mar 16, 1983). Tape 12, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3343)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Professor Philip S. Foner, Marxist Tradition in the USA. Tape 13, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3347)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Professor H. L. Parsons, Creativity in Marxist Thought. Tape 14, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3350)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. John Pittman, Marx and the USA Working Class. Tape 15, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3354)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Cassette Symposium. Death of Karl Marx. (Mar 19, 1983). Tape 16, Mar 16, 1983 - May 22, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3358)
    - Gus Hall, Speech at Daily World Fundraising Dinner. Boston, MA, Mar 20, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3285)
    - Moses Mabhida (General Secretary of the Communist Party of South Africa), Press Conference, Mar 23, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3288)
    - Henry Winston, on Paul Robeson. People's School of Marxist Studies Graduation Ceremony, Unity Center, New York, NY (Side 1). Angela Davis and James Steele (Side 2)., Mar 24, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3290)
    - Henry Winston, on Paul Robeson. People's School of Marxist Studies Graduation Ceremony, Unity Center, New York, NY, Mar 24, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3291)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference. Includes Gus Hall, Moses Mabhida, Leith Mullings, Lou Diskin, Mar 26, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3294)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Conference, Conclusion. Tape 6, Mar 26, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3295)
    - Moses Mabhida, Speech. Introduction by Kevin Mercadel. Harlem, New York, NY. Tape 1, Mar 30, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3292)
    - Moses Mabhida, Speech. Introduction by Kevin Mercadel. Harlem, New York, NY. Tape 2, Mar 30, 1983 (Box 51, Cassette 3293)
    - Unity Coalition, Progressive Electoral Options in 1984 - How to Fight Reaganomics. Includes Gus Hall, Barry Commoner, Marge Harrison, Professor Manning Marable, Jane Benedict and Professor Angela Gillian. Marc Ballroom, New York, NY. Tape 1 *, May 3, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3374)
    - Unity Coalition, Progressive Electoral Options in 1984 - How to Fight Reaganomics. Questions and Answers, Summary and Statement. Tape 2 *, May 3, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3375)
    - Mary Kalb, Lecture on United Front Coalition Work in the American South. Includes Mary Licht (?), May 5, 1983 (Box 58, Cassette 1293)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Rally. Henry Winston, Speech. Tape 1, May 22, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3376)
    - Karl Marx Centenary Rally. Henry Winston, Speech. Tape 2, May 22, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3377)
    - People's World Banquet. Includes Gus Hall. Seattle, WA, Jun 11, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3379)
    - Recruitment Meetings. Washington, D.C., Portland, OR, Seattle, WA, Jun 12, 1983 - Jun 13, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3381)
    - Victor Perlo, World Economic Developments and the Capitalist System. Tape 2, Jun 16, 1983 (Box 32, Cassette 4894)
    - Victor Perlo, World Economic Developments and the Capitalist System. Includes Discussion. Tape 3, Jun 16, 1983 (Box 32, Cassette 4895)
    - Evaluation of Regional School. San Francisco, CA, Aug 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3382)
    - Gus Hall, Press Conference on Central America, Aug 2, 1983 (Box 55, Cassette 4193)
    - Southern Christian Leadership Conference, 26th Convention. Includes President Joseph Lowry, and Spirituals. Tape 1, Aug 24, 1983 - Aug 27, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3383)
    - Southern Christian Leadership Conference, 26th Convention. Includes President Joseph Lowry. Tape 2, Aug 24, 1983 - Aug 27, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3384)
    - Conference on African-American Equality. Includes Charlene Mitchell, Robert Lindsay and George Meyers, Sep 10, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3385)
    - Daily Worker Conference. Includes Mike Zagarell, Rick Nagin and Gus Hall, Sep 24, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3386)
    - Industrial Concentration Conference. Gus Hall, Opening. Cleveland, OH, Oct 1, 1983 - Oct 2, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3387)
    - Gus Hall, Recruitment Speech and Remarks at Trade Union Commission Meeting. Chicago, IL, Oct 5, 1983 - Oct 6, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3388)
    - Rally to Save Southworks. Gus Hall, Speech. Farolito Club, Chicago, IL, Oct 7, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3389)
    - Gus Hall, Recruitment Meeting at Pilsen Committee. New York, NY, Oct 10, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3390)
    - Political Affairs Forum on Marx and Economics. Gus Hall, Introduction, Oct 23, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3395)
    - Political Affairs Forum on Marx and Economics. Gus Hall, Introduction. Tape 1, Oct 23, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3396)
    - Political Affairs Forum on Marx and Economics. Includes Barry Cohen, Faye Hanson, and William Tabb. Tape 2, Oct 23, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3398)
    - Political Affairs Forum on Marx and Economics. Includes Gus Hall and Barry Cohen, Oct 23, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3399)
    - Political Affairs Forum on Marx and Economics. Includes Victor Perlo, Walteen Grady and Gregory Tarpinian. Tape 3, Oct 23, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3402)
    - Political Affairs Forum on Marx and Economics. Includes Maurice Jackson, Rubin Horne. Tape 4, Oct 23, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3405)
    - Norman Goldberg, The Materialist Conception of Art. Lecture 1, Oct 25, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3407)
    - Norman Goldberg, The Materialist Conception of Art. Lecture 2, Nov 1, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3411)
    - Workshop on African-American Equality. Tape 1, Nov 10, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3412)
    - Workshop on African-American Equality. Tape 2, Nov 10, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3413)
    - Joseph Figueiredo, [on the New Bedford Textile Worker's Strike of 1928], Nov 11, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3414)
    - Gus Hall, Speech at Rally. Cleveland, OH, Nov 13, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3415)
    - Jessica Smith Memorial, Nov 27, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3417)
    - Gus Hall, Report to the Graduates of the Marxist School on the 23rd Convention of the CPUSA, Dec 9, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3419)
    - Trade Union Meeting. Gus Hall, Opening Remarks. Essex Hotel, Chicago, IL, Dec 17, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3421)
    - Rally to Save Southworks. Gus Hall, Speech. Farolito Club, Chicago, IL, Dec 18, 1983 (Box 54, Cassette 3422)
    - Mary Licht, Lecture on Len Levenson, Dec 19, 1983 (Box 58, Cassette 1290)
    - Gus Hall, Election Tactics for 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3426)
    - Gus Hall, on the 1984 Election / Responses from Listeners to Communist Party Radio Campaign (Box 54, Cassette 3427)
    - Gus Hall, Speeches. 1984 Campaign Speech, on the Chernobyl Explosion, May Day 1985 and on the Death of Henry Winston, 1984; 1985; 1986 (Box 54, Cassette 3425)
    - International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers Convention, Update. Tape 6, [1984] (Box 55, Cassette 4282)
    - Nominating Conference. Includes Henry Winston, Jarvis Tyner, James Steele, Peggy (?) and Gus Hall, Acceptance Speech., Jan 24, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3428)
    - Gus Hall, Press Conference. New Hartford, CT and Yale Political Union, New Haven, CT, Jan 31, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3429)
    - Gus Hall, Press Conference, Feb 22, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3432)
    - Gus Hall, Press Conferences. Unknown location and Columbia Union, New York, NY, Feb 22, 1984 - Feb 23, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3433)
    - Gus Hall, Press Conference. Columbia Union, New York, NY, Feb 23, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3434)
    - AIMS / Herbert Aptheker Dinner. Includes Leith Mullings, Johnetta Cole, Vinnie Burroughs, and Ernest De Maio. Auditorium of Local 1199, New York, NY. Tape 1, Feb 26, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3437)
    - AIMS / Herbert Aptheker Dinner. Includes Henry Winston Introducing Herbert Aptheker. Auditorium of Local 1199, New York, NY. Tape 2, Feb 26, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3438)
    - AIMS / Herbert Aptheker Dinner. Includes Herbert Aptheker. Auditorium of Local 1199, New York, NY. Tape 3, Feb 26, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3439)
    - Gus Hall, Stanford University Law Forum, Mar 13, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3440)
    - Gus Hall, San Jose College, CA, Mar 14, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3441)
    - Gus Hall, Membership Meeting on Election Campaign. Boston, MA, Mar 25, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3443)
    - Gus Hall, Boston University Free School. Boston, MA, Mar 26, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3444)
    - Gus Hall, Press Conference. Boston, MA, Mar 26, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3445)
    - Gus Hall, Press Conference. Portland, ME, Mar 28, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3446)
    - Gus Hall, Midwest Election Campaign Emergency Meeting. Chicago, IL. Tape 1, Apr 1, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3447)
    - Gus Hall, Midwest Election Campaign Emergency Meeting. Chicago, IL. Tape 2, Apr 1, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3448)
    - Jarvis Tyner, on Elections, Apr 6, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3449)
    - Gus Hall, May Day Address. Union Square, New York, NY, Apr 28, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3450)
    - Gus Hall, Daily World Affair. Montclair, NJ, Apr 29, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3453)
    - Gus Hall, John Abt Dinner, May 11, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3454)
    - Jewish Affairs Dinner. Includes Herbert Aptheker, Charlene Mitchell, Lewis Moroze and Gus Hall. Tape 1, Jun 10, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3455)
    - Jewish Affairs Dinner. Includes Genrikis Zimanas and Aaron Vergelis (Representatives from the Soviet Union). Tape 2, Jun 10, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3456)
    - Jewish Affairs Dinner. Gus Hall, On the Big Lie [the Soviet Threat], Jun 10, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3457)
    - David Wheeler, on Vietnam Veterans. Los Angeles, CA, Jun 14, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3458)
    - Gus Hall, Address at Picnic. Arrow Park, [NY?], Jun 23, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3459)
    - Gus Hall, Press Conference, Jun 28, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3460)
    - Angela Davis, Harlem Election Rally, Jul 17, 1984 (Box 64, Cd 3462, Box 54, Cassette 3462)
    - Economic Commission, Menshikov Discussion, Jul 21, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3461)
    - Gus Hall, Report to Daily World Staff Regarding Election Campaign, Jul 29, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3463)
    - Tribute to Irving Herman, Aug 4, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3464)
    - Henry Winston, Lecture. Also includes James [Jackson], Aug 7, 1984 (Box 59, Cassette 1086)
    - Political Affairs Cultural Conference. Angela Davis. University of Colorado, Boulder, CO, Oct 3, 1984 (Box 64, Cd 3471 (disks 1-2), Box 54, Cassette 3471)
    - Political Affairs Cultural Conference. Henrik Borovik. University of Colorado, Boulder, CO, Oct 3, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3465)
    - Political Affairs Cultural Conference. Michael Parenti. University of Colorado, Boulder, CO, Oct 3, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3468)
    - Gus Hall, Election Campaign Press Conference. Cleveland, OH, Oct 4, 1984 (Box 55, Cassette 4194)
    - Gus Hall, Election Campaign Press Conference. Youngstown, OH, Oct 4, 1984 (Box 55, Cassette 4195)
    - Election Campaign Rally. Gus Hall, Speech. First Unitarian Church, Pittsburgh, PA, Oct 4, 1984 (Box 55, Cassette 4262)
    - Gus Hall, Election Campaign Rally. Swingo's, Cleveland, OH, Oct 6, 1984 (Box 55, Cassette 4196)
    - Gus Hall, Election Campaign Rally. St. Andrew's Hall, Detroit, MI, Oct 7, 1984 (Box 55, Cassette 4197)
    - Henry Winston, Report on Ethiopia, Oct 10, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3472)
    - Gus Hall, Press Conference. Washington, DC, Oct 17, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3473)
    - Gus Hall, Press Conference. Fireman's Mall, Baltimore, MD, Oct 18, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3474)
    - Gus Hall, Rally. Baltimore, MD, Oct 18, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3475)
    - Gus Hall, Press Conference. New York, NY, Oct 19, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3476)
    - Gus Hall, Fundraiser, Oct 19, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3477)
    - Election Campaign Rally. Includes Jarvis Tyner, James Steele and Gus Hall. New York, NY. Tape 1, Oct 21, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3478)
    - Election Campaign Rally. Includes Gus Hall. New York, NY. Tape 2, Oct 21, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3479)
    - Election Campaign Rally. Includes Angela Davis. New York, NY. Tape 3, Oct 21, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3480)
    - Gus Hall, Rally. Bismarck Hotel, Chicago, IL, Oct 28, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3481)
    - Gus Hall, Speech. Milwaukee, WI, Oct 30, 1984 (Box 56, Cassette 4701)
    - Press Conference. Marc Plaza Hotel, Milwaukee, WI, Oct 30, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3482)
    - Gus Hall, Rally. Seattle, WA, Nov 1, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3483)
    - Dump Reagan Rally. Gus Hall, Speech. San Francisco and Oakland, CA, Nov 3 [1984?] (Box 52, Cassette 4007)
    - Dump Reagan Rally. Includes Angela Davis. Convention Center, Los Angeles, CA, Nov 4, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3485)
    - Dump Reagan Rally. Includes Gus Hall. Convention Center, Los Angeles, CA, Nov 4, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3484)
    - Gus Hall, The 1984 Elections - What Happened, Where Do We Go From Here? Unity Center, New York, NY, Nov 16, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3486)
    - Gus Hall, Press Conference. Tape 1, Dec 21, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3491)
    - Gus Hall, Press Conference. Tape 2, Dec 21, 1984 (Box 54, Cassette 3492)
    - Henry Winston, on the 40th Anniversary of World War II. Moscow, 1985 (?) (Box 59, Cassette 967)
    - Henry Winston, Ethiopia - Eyewitness Report. Powell State Office Building, New York, NY. Tape 1, Feb 1, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3523)
    - Henry Winston, Ethiopia - Eyewitness Report. Powell State Office Building, New York, NY. Tape 2, Feb 1, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3524)
    - Henry Winston, Ethiopia - Eyewitness Report (Edited). Powell State Office Building, New York, NY, Feb 1, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3525)
    - Chile Solidarity Secretariat. International Women's Day at P.S. 41, New York, NY / Music, Mar 16, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3528)
    - May Day. Tape 1, May 1, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3529)
    - Gus Hall, May Day, May 1, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3530)
    - Young Communist League, 2nd Anniversary Celebration. Includes James Steele. Tape 2, May 4, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3532)
    - George Meyers, Racism. Tape 1, May 7, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3533)
    - Young Communist League. Discussion on Youth Unemployment, May 7, 1985 (Box 32, Cassette 4888)
    - National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression (NAARPR) Rally. Frederick Douglass Junior High School, New York, NY. Tape 1, May 17, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3534)
    - National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression (NAARPR) Rally. Frederick Douglass Junior High School, New York, NY. Tape 2, May 17, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3535)
    - Phillip Bonosky, on Afghanistan, May 19, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3537)
    - Charlene Mitchell, on Afro-American Equality and Unemployment, May 21, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3538)
    - Afro-American Equality Conference, Jun 15, 1985 (Box 36, Cassette 921)
    - Afro-American Equality Conference. Gus Hall, Jun 15, 1985 (Box 39, Cassette 2012)
    - Afro-American Equality Conference. Gus Hall on New Developments, Jun 15, 1985 (Box 42, Cassette 2743)
    - Afro-American Equality Conference. Tape 1, Jun 15, 1985 (Box 36, Cassette 826)
    - Afro-American Equality Conference. Workshop on Ideology. [Condition poor: creation of user copy may pose problems. Contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu], Jun 15, 1985 (Box 36, Cassette 831)
    - Afro-American Equality Conference. Workshop on Ideology / Henry Winston, Concentration on Harlem. [Condition poor: creation of user copy may pose problems. Contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu], Jun 15, 1985; May 5, 1986 (Box 36, Cassette 835)
    - National Party School. Gus Hall, Opportunism. Tape 1, Jun 15, 1985 or Jul 15, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3497)
    - National Party School. Gus Hall, Opportunism. Tape 2, Jun 15, 1985 or Jul 15, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3494)
    - Jarvis Tyner, Daily World Picnic, Jun 23, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3495)
    - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Rally. Presenting Two Ambulances to the Ambassador of Nicaragua. San Francisco, CA, Jul 1985 (Box 32, Cassette 5001)
    - Memorial for Sonia Kolkin. Includes Gert Decker, Robert Merims, Nettie Zimmerman, Jarvis Tyner, and Mim Kelber / Memorial for Alex Kolkin. Includes Lewis Moroze, Si Gerson, Mim Kelber, Ed Stark, Henry Winston, and Gertrude Decker, Jul 24, 1985; Aug 21, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3499)
    - Gus Hall, Speech. Tape 1, Jul 15, 1985 (Box 32, Cassette 4931)
    - Secretariat. Victor Perlo, The Dollar Crisis and What it Means to You, Jul 16, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3498)
    - Henry Winston, Educational. Tape 1, Jul 30, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3500)
    - Henry Winston, Educational. Tape 2, Jul 30, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3501)
    - Daniel Rubin, The Working Class: Class Struggle, the Working Class Outlook and the Source of Profits and Surplus Value (Topic 2), Aug 4, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3503)
    - Daniel Rubin, Dialectic Materialism: Our Philosophy and Tool of Class Struggle and Methodology, Objective Process and Estimating the Political Situation (Topic 3), Aug 6, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3504)
    - Jarvis Tyner, Strategic and Political Policy of the Party (Topic 4), Aug 7, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3505)
    - Carol Pittman, The Struggle for Full Equality and against Racism / Hector Rivera, Puerto Rican Equality and Independence (Topic 5), Aug 8, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3506)
    - Hector Rivera, Puerto Rican Equality and Independence (continued) / Carol Pittman, The Struggle for Women's Equality (Topic 6) / The Club, Discussion (Topic 7), Aug 9, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3507)
    - Carol Pittman, Youth Cadre Development (Topic 8), Aug 11, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3508)
    - Memorial for Alex Kolkin. Includes Lewis Moroze, Si Gerson, Mim Kelber, Henry Winston, David Selzer, and Gertrude Decker, Aug 21, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3509)
    - On Post-Revolution Afghanistan / Ronald Reagan, on the 40th Anniversary of the United Nations Charter, Sept 25, 1985; Oct 24, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3510)
    - Gus Hall, 66th Anniversary [of the CPUSA] Rally. Los Angeles, CA, Sep 30, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3511)
    - Gus Hall, Interview with The Daily Northwestern. Evanston, IL, Oct 4, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3512)
    - Recruitment Meeting. Includes Gus Hall. West Side, Chicago, IL, Oct 5, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3513)
    - Gus Hall, 66th Anniversary [of the CPUSA] Rally. Essex Inn, Chicago, IL, Oct 6, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3514)
    - Gus Hall, on the Geneva Summit, Oct 14, 1985 (Box 42, Cassette 2684)
    - Gus Hall, on the Geneva Summit (5 mins), Oct 14, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3515)
    - Gus Hall, on the Star Wars [Geneva] Summit. Unity Center, New York, NY, Nov 3, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3517)
    - Gus Hall, on the Star Wars [Geneva] Summit. Includes Jarvis Tyner. Unity Center, New York, NY, Nov 3, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3518)
    - Gus Hall, on the Star Wars [Geneva] Summit. Unity Center, New York, NY. Tape 1, Nov 3, 1985 (Box 32, Cassette 4876)
    - Gus Hall, on the Star Wars [Geneva] Summit. Unity Center, New York, NY. Tape 2, Nov 3, 1985 (Box 32, Cassette 4877)
    - Gus Hall, Obstacles on the Path to the Reagan-Gorbachev [Geneva] Summit. Princeton University, Princeton, NJ, Nov 7, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3520)
    - Gus Hall, on Foreign Debt and Discussion. Tape 3, Nov 12, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3539)
    - George Meyers, Report on AFL-CIO Convention, Nov 19, 1985 (Box 30, Cassette 1559)
    - Gus Hall, Report on the [Geneva] Summit, Nov 21, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3540)
    - Andimba Toivo ya Toivo (General Secretary of the South West Africa People's Organization), Lecture. Tape 9, Dec 11, 1985 (Box 32, Cassette 4900)
    - Gus Hall, The "Chips and Robot" [High-Tech] Revolution and Its Relation to Production, Jobs and Corporate Profit, Dec 11, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3541)
    - Discussion in Preparation for National Party School, Dec 18, 1985 (Box 53, Cassette 3542)